

# **Igor Freitas Couto**

Porto, Portugal igor.fcouto@gmail.com +351 913 986 672



#### **PROFILE**

Experienced developer with a strong 6-year background in .NET technologies, and software architecture. Deeply committed to creating software solutions that drive positive change for both the company and its clients. A strong advocate of agile methodologies, consistently implementing industry best practices to streamline project workflow and enhance productivity.

#### **SKILLS**

- C# (.NET)
- Angular

- Git

- Unit testing
- Acceptance Testing
- JavaScript
  TypeScript
  HTML5 & CSS
  e2e Testing
  SCRUM and Kanban
  Redis
  Entity Framework
  Bash script
  - Clean Code

- Postgres
- SQL Server

- Dapper

- AWS Cloud
- Docker
- GitHub Actions

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Checkout.com** — Full Time Software Engineer

AUG 2023 — PRESENT

Developing and enhancing features for various services, notably in report generation, client settlements, invoices, and related areas. My work involves creating robust and efficient solutions that improve the financial reporting and reconciliation processes, contributing significantly to the company's operational excellence and customer satisfaction

#### **Lambda3 Consulting — Full Time Software Developer**

OCT 2020 - AUG 2023

Worked on projects aligned with Agile philosophy. Participated in the development of a chat and customer service system for one of the main retail chains in Brazil, which led to an increased market share, especially during the pandemic. Developed a banking account system for a company in the loyalty segment, using points redeemable through cashback. For a fast-growing fintech company, created an integration system that generated bank slips based on customer orders.

## Delage Logistics & Supply Chain — Full Time Systems Analyst

MAR 2018 — OCT 2020

Developed a Warehouse Management System and related logistics software. Conducted client visits for product sales and deployments in Brazil and Argentina. Designed and implemented system interfaces for third-party integration (ERPs and automation), and maintained legacy systems. Created APIs, Windows Services and SDKs.

# **EDUCATION**

### Federal University of Juiz de Fora

Made significant contributions and academic activities:

- Member of junior enterprise CODE
- Member of Group for Computer Graphics, Image and Vision
- Member of Computer Science Tutorial Education Group where I participated in the development of EducAR Quadrics and LocalizAR UFJF apps
- Course taught to 40 students about 3D modeling
- Co-author of two academic articles [1] [2]

#### **LANGUAGES**

**Portuguese** Native Speaker from Brazil **English** 

**Professional Working Proficiency** 

**Spanish** 

**Limited Working Proficiency**